polar3d.com 2019-08-28

# Polar 3D Privacy Policy

## **POLAR3D PRIVACY POLICY**

Last updated August 1, 2019

Polar3D, LLC ("Polar3D") is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to those who visit the websites ("Sites") owned and operated by Polar3D and located at polar3d.com and about.polar3d.com. This Privacy Policy describes how Polar3D collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. The use of information collected through our Sites shall be limited to the purpose of providing, supporting, and improving the services offered by the Sites.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at support@polar3d.com.

### **Privacy Compliance**

With respect to personal data received or transferred, Polar3D is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Polar3D may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Polar3D complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Polar3D has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

### **Your Privacy Choices & Means**

Your personal information is kept strictly confidential and will not be shared or sold to third parties except as necessary to deliver our services. In the event Polar3D will need to share information outside of our normal services, we will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their Personal Information is (a) to be disclosed to a third party acting as a controller, or (b) to be used for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. For sensitive personal information, Polar3D will give individuals the opportunity to affirmatively and explicitly consent (opt-in) to the disclosure of their Sensitive Personal Information to (a) a third party acting as a controller or (b) the use of the information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. Polar3D will provide individuals with reasonable (especially clear and conspicuous, readily available) mechanisms to exercise their choices and includes, without limitation, the ability to delete their account and all Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information associated therewith, if any. See below and [Privacy Policy FAQs](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=Privacy-Policy-FAQs-1-5) for additional information.

### **How Do We Collect, Use and Share Your Personal Information and Other Information?**

#### **Collection**

We may collect the following personal information from you within the Sites:

  * Contact Information, such as name, email address, mailing address, or phone number;
  * Information about your organization, such as the name of your school and district or the name of your business.

We may collect the following personal information from you when you use our Sites:

  * Contact Information, such as name, email address, mailing address, IP address, geographic location, or phone number;
  * Unique Identifiers, such as your email address.

We may collect the following personal information from our Single Sign-On providers when you use our Sites:

  * Your email address, first name, and last name;
  * Your preferred public display name;
  * Your profile image.

The information collected from our Single Sign-On providers is saved in your Account profile within Polar3D's databases. At any time you can change or remove the above information via your [account settings](https://polar3d.com/member-settings) within the Sites.

#### **Use**

We may use the personal information collected from within the Sites or when you use the Sites to:

  * Provide you with the services of the Sites
  * Send you communication from the Sites
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you promotional and marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Facilitate your transactions with other users when you use our Sites

Of the information collected from the Single Sign-On providers, only your profile image and display name are disclosed to other members of the Sites. (Please note, in some instances the Single Sign-On providers may provide a display name constructed from your first and last names or even use your email address. Change your display name via the [Account settings page](https://polar3d.com/member-settings) to suit your preferences.) Should you use devices (e.g., 3D printers) of other members through the Sites, your email address will be disclosed to the managers of those devices. That so that they may contact you should the need arise.

In the case of Google's Single Sign-On, the Sites also ask your consent to access (read-only) your Google Classrooms and Google Drive, should you use either. This is done to assist you with the creation of classroom groups within the Sites, and to allow you to access 3D models you might have stored in Google Drive. Classroom data is restricted to the names of the classrooms and the students enrolled. When you choose to create a classroom group within the Sites, you have the option of drawing information from your active and provisioned Google Classrooms. The only retained Google Classroom data is the unique Google Classroom identifier associated with a given Google Classroom. Any 3D model you choose to access from Google Drive is copied to the Sites, instantiating a copy of the file data which is then accessible to only your Account at the Sites. You may subsequently choose to share that file copy with other members of the Sites; however, without your explicit action, the copy is kept private to your own Account.

#### **Share**

Except as outlined in this Policy, your information will never be sold to or shared with other companies or organizations for commercial purposes or otherwise. We may transfer personal information to our sub-contractors that help us provide our Sites. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our sub-contractors. Such sub-contractors may include third-party payment processors who process your credit card and other payment information for Polar3D but are otherwise not permitted to store, retain or use such information.  

We are committed to the responsible onward transfer of data to third parties, and work to ensure that our sub-contractors provide the same level of protection as is required under the Privacy Shield Principles. We will remain liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if a sub-contractor that we engage to process personal information on our behalf does so in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to damage. 

### **Correction or Removal of Personal Information**

In most cases, you can correct or remove your personal information via your [account settings](https://polar3d.com/member-settings) page within the Sites.

If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at support@polar3d.com

### **Other Information**

Other information such as End-Customer device models (e.g., 3D printers), IP address, or usage patterns are also captured by the Sites. This information is used by Polar3D to support your usage of the Sites and any devices managed through the Sites. Polar3D may share your name, location, email address, and device usage information with the device's manufacturer or distributors.

### **Retention of Personal Information**

We retain Personal Data we process for as long as an Account is active or as needed to provide the services of the Sites. If you wish to terminate your Account or request that we no longer use Your Data, please contact us at support@polar3d.com. We will retain Your Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, maintain accurate financial and other records, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We delete all Your Data on the expiry of 14 days after the termination of your Account, except as otherwise prohibited by applicable law.

### **Use of Cookies**

When you use our Sites, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a “cookie” or similar file/technologies. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive, not on the Polar3D websites. We do not use cookies to spy on you or otherwise invade your privacy. They cannot invade your hard drive and steal information. We use cookies to help you navigate the Sites as easily as possible, and to remember information about your current session. These are referred to as "Session Cookies" and they are removed from your system when you close the web browser or turn off the computer. You must enable cookies on your web browser to use the Sites.

### **Log Files**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

### **Social Media Features**

Our Sites may include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button, the “Share This” button or interactive mini-programs. Where we have your consent, these features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

### **Links to Third Party Sites**

Our Sites contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by Polar3D. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites or third parties. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Sites and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal information.

### **Public Forums**

Our Sites offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forums, contact us at support@polar3d.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know that we are unable to do so and why.

### **Single Sign-On**

You can log in to our Sites using sign-in services such as offered by Google, Facebook, and Microsoft. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address. Services like Google and Facebook give you the option to post information about your activities on our Sites to your profile page, to share information with others within your network. In the case of Google, you further have the option of sharing information with Google Classrooms and accessing 3D models stored in Google Drive.

### **Communications from the Sites**

We may use your email address to send our newsletters and/or marketing communications. If you no longer wish to receive these communications, you can opt out by following the instructions contained in the emails you receive or by contacting us at support@polar3d.com.

We will send you announcements related to the Sites on occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our Sites are temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of communications which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you may deactivate your Account.

### **Advertising**

We partner with third-party advertising networks to either display advertising on our Sites or to manage our advertising on other websites. Our ad network partner may use cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on our Sites and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests (this will only be the case if we have your consent in certain locations).

### **Protection of Information**

The Sites have industry standard security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. When you provide us with sensitive information (such as credit card information or login credentials), we will encrypt that information via Secure Socket Layer (SSL).

While there is no such thing as “perfect security” on the Internet, we take all reasonable steps to ensure the safety of your personal information. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Sites and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we receive your personal information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

If you have questions about our security you can contact us at [support@polar3d.com](mailto:support@polar3d.com)

### **Testimonials**

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Sites which may contain personal information. Prior to posting the testimonial, we obtain the customer's consent to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed, please contact us at support@polar3d.com.

### **Corrections and Updates**

Upon request Polar3D will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at support@polar3d.com.

We allow users of the Sites to access, update or modify their information by clicking on the Settings item in the account navigation menu or by contacting us at support@polar3d.com. We seek to respond to requests for access or modification as soon as possible and within reasonable time frame.

### **Amendments**

Amendments to this Policy will be posted to this URL and will be effective when posted. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our Sites prior to the change becoming effective. You should frequently visit this Policy to check for amendments. Your continued use of these Sites following the posting of any amendment, modification, or change to this Policy shall constitute your acceptance of the amendments to this Policy. You can choose to discontinue use of these Sites, if you do not accept the terms of this Policy, or any modified version of this Policy.

### **Legal Disclosure**

We reserve the right to disclose your personal data as required by applicable law, in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process served on us.

In the event Polar3D goes through a business transition, such as a merger or acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your user account and personal data will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email and via a prominent notice on our Sites of any such change in ownership or control. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

### **Contacting Polar3D**

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Polar3D commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. Individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Polar3D at:

**support@polar3d.com or via postal mail at Polar 3D, LLC, 6102 Madison Road, Cincinnati, OH 45227, USA**

Polar3D has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU.

Under certain circumstances, you may have the option to engage in binding arbitration to resolve your complaint by following the guidelines provided by Annex I of the Privacy Shield Framework. For more information, please visit [Annex I ](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction)
